Guide to the Richard Courant Papers MC 150
New York University Archives
- Series II: Files from the Office of Richard Courant
  - Subseries A: General Files
    - Szego, G., 1944-1950 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - "T" Misc., 1938-1960 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - "T" Misc. (1 of 2), 1961-1971 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - "T" Misc. (2 of 2), 1961-1971 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Tamarkin, J.D. and Willy Feller, Partial Differential Equations--Chapters I-II, 1941 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Tamarkin, J.D. and Willy Feller, Partial Differential Equations--Chapters III, 1941 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Tamarkin, J.D. and Willy Feller, Partial Differential Equations--Chapters IV-V, 1941 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Tamarkin, J.D. and Willy Feller, Partial Differential Equations--Chapters VI, 1941 (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Tamarkin, J.D. and Willy Feller, Partial Differential Equations--Chapters VII, 1941 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Task Force Reports (NYU), 1958 (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - Task Force Reports (NYU), 1958 (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - Taylor, G.I., 1948 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Tayor, Mary--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1926 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Tblisi Meeting, 1962, 1969 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Technical University of Denmark, 1968-1969 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Teller, Edward, 1952-1960 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Teller, Edward, 1961-1963 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Terracini, Alessandro, 1940-1946 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - "Theory of Functions of a Complex Variable", 1938-1939 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - "Theory of Functions of a Complex Variable", 1939 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - "Theory of Functions of a Complex Variable" (1 of 2), 1944-1945 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - "Theory of Functions of a Complex Variable" (2 of 2), 1944-1945 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - "Theory of Functions of a Complex Variable" p. 162-173, 1944-1945 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Thomas, J.W., 1938-1941 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Thompson, Dorothy, 1941 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - Thompson, Philip D., 1950-1951 (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - Thorne, Perley L., 1946-1949 (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - Thullen, Peter, 1944-1948 (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - Thullen, Peter--"Remarks on the Morbidity Rate", 1961 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - Tietze, Heinrich, 1947-1948 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - Tietze, Heinrich--Math Drawings [use copies], undated (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - Tietze, Heinrich--Math Drawings [originals], undated (Box 87, Folder 21)
    - Tietze, Heinrich-- Probleme--Figures, undated (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Tietze, Heinrich-- Probleme--IX, undated (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Tietze, Heinrich-- Probleme--X, undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Tietze, Heinrich-- Probleme--XI, undated (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Tietze, Heinrich-- Probleme--XII, undated (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Tietze, Heinrich-- Probleme--XIII, undated (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Tietze, Heinrich-- Probleme--XIV, undated (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Tietze, Heinrich-- Probleme--XV, undated (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Time, 1943 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Titt, E.W., 1938, 1947 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Todd, John and Olga, 1943-1959 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Toeplitz, Erna, 1927-1947 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Toeplitz, Otto-- The Development of the Infinitesimal Calculus Vol. I (1 of 3), 1958 (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - Toeplitz, Otto-- The Development of the Infinitesimal Calculus Vol. I (2 of 3), 1958 (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - Toeplitz, Otto-- The Development of the Infinitesimal Calculus Vol. I (3 of 3), 1958 (Box 88, Folder 15)
    - Touart, C.--"Theoretical Interior Ballistics of Line Wedge-Shaped Charges", 1951 (Box 88, Folder 16)
    - Travel--Denmark, Poland, Russia, Western Europe 4/30-7/4/60, 1959-1960 (Box 88, Folder 17)
    - Travel--Europe--Diary, 1947 (Box 88, Folder 18)
    - Travel--Europe, 1947-1948 (Box 88, Folder 19)
    - Travel--Europe 5/16-8/17/50, 1950 (Box 88, Folder 20)
    - Travel--Europe (with Keller), 1951 (Box 88, Folder 21)
    - Travel--Europe, 1952 (Box 88, Folder 22)
    - Travel--Europe, 1953 (Box 88, Folder 23)
    - Travel--Europe, 1954 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Travel--Europe, 1955-1956 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Travel--Europe, 1957 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Travel--Europe, 1958 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Travel--Europe--Summary of Report, 1960 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Travel--Europe, 1963 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Travel--Misc. Itineraries, etc., 1960 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Travel--U.S.S.R., 1967 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Travel--U.S.S.R. 10/20-11/11/1967 (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Travel--U.S.S.R. 4/2-4/4/1970 (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Travel--Venezuela, 1957 (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - Travel--Washington 4/13/1956 (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - Travel--West Coast, 1954 (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Tricomi, Francesco, 1951-1956 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Trilling, Leon, 1948 (Box 89, Folder 15)
    - Truesdell, C., 1953-1960 (Box 89, Folder 16)
    - Tschen, Yu-why, 1943-1945 (Box 89, Folder 17)
    - Tsiang, Sho-min, 1946 (Box 89, Folder 18)
    - Tukey, John W., 1946-1949 (Box 89, Folder 19)
    - Turbo-Encabulator, 1944 (Box 89, Folder 20)
    - "U" Misc., 1945-1966 (Box 89, Folder 21)
    - "Ueber die Methode des Dirichletschen Prinzipes", undated (Box 89, Folder 22)
    - UNESCO, 1956-1960 (Box 89, Folder 23)
    - Union Carbide & Carbon Corp., 1954-1956 (Box 89, Folder 24)
    - "Unsolved Problems Concerning Least Area (With Experimental Demonstrations", 1963 (Box 89, Folder 25)
    - U.S. Air Force--Tullahoma, Tenn., 1946-1953 (Box 89, Folder 26)
    - U.S. National Committee for Maintenance, 1957-1959 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Navy (see "Office of Naval Research"), 1964 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - U.S.-U.S.S.R. Questionnaires, 1966 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - U.S.S.R.--General, 1959-1960 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - U.S.S.R.--General, 1961 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - U.S.S.R.--General, 1962 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - U.S.S.R.--General, 1963 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - U.S.S.R.--Information, 1963 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - U.S.S.R.--Moscow Meeting, October 1967, 1967 October-November (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - U.S.S.R.--Novosibirisk Meeting, Aug. 1963, 1962 September-December (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - U.S.S.R.--Novosibirisk Meeting, Aug. 1963, 1962 September-1963 January (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - U.S.S.R.--Novosibirisk Meeting, Aug. 1963 (1 of 2), 1963 February-July (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - U.S.S.R.--Novosibirisk Meeting, Aug. 1963 (2 of 2), 1963 February-July (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - U.S.S.R.--Novosibirisk Meeting, Aug. 1963, 1963 April-June (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - U.S.S.R.--Novosibirisk Meeting, Aug. 1963, 1963 July-November, 1965 February (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - "V" Misc., 1944-1968 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - "Variational Methods and Boundary Value Problems", 1941 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - "Variational Methods for the Solution of Problems of Equilibrium and Vibrations", 1941 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Veblen, Oswald, 1943-1959 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Vietnam, 1966 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Visitors (CIMS), 1963-1966 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - von Kármán, Theodore, 1941-1959 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - von Kármán, Theodore, 1944-1961 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - von Mises, Hilda, 1943-1955 (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - von Neumann, 1946-1957 (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - "W" Misc. (1 of 2), 1941-1960 (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - "W" Misc. (2 of 2), 1941-1960 (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - "W" Misc., 1960-1971 (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - Waerden, B. L. van der, 1945-1957 (Box 91, Folder 14)
    - Waerden, B. L. van der, 1945-1964 (Box 91, Folder 15)
    - Wagner, Herbert, 1946 (Box 91, Folder 16)
    - Walther, Alwin (1 of 2), 1909-1959 (Box 91, Folder 17)
    - Walther, Alwin (1 of 2), 1909-1959 (Box 91, Folder 18)
    - War Department, 1946 (Box 91, Folder 19)
    - Warren Weaver Hall, 1965-1970 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Warren Weaver Hall--Dedication Speech, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Watson Laboratories, 1946-1948 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Waverly Press, 1941-1968 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 4, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 4, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 4, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 4, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 4, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 4, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 4, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 11)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 4, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 6, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 13)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 7, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 14)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 7, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 15)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 7, 1961 (Box 92, Folder 16)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II Copy 8, 1961 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Waverly Press-- Page Proof Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II "Master Copy", 1961 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Weaver, Warren (1 of 2), 1936-1960 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Weaver, Warren (2 of 2), 1936-1960 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Weaver, Warren (1 of 2), 1961-1971 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Weaver, Warren (2 of 2), 1961-1971 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Weaver, Warren--Remarks at NYU Trustee Dinner, 1964 (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Weber, Ernst, 1942-1953 (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - Weber, Ernst--"Transient Analysis of Electrical Networks", 1941 (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Wecken (St. Louis Laboratoire de Recherches), 1953 (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - Wegner, Udo, 1949-1957 (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - Wei, Si Laun--Dissertation--Göttingen, 1925 (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Weinstein, Alexander, 1940-1954 (Box 93, Folder 13)
    - Westchester Science Fair, 1956-1960 (Box 93, Folder 14)
    - Wever, F., 1960 (Box 93, Folder 15)
    - Weyl, F.J., 1953-1967 (Box 93, Folder 16)
    - Weyl, Helene, 1948, undated (Box 93, Folder 17)
    - Weyl, Hermann, 1947-1957 (Box 93, Folder 18)
    - Weyl Report--Courant Remarks, 1953 (Box 93, Folder 19)
    - "What is Mathematics?" Lectures, undated (Box 93, Folder 20)
    - What is Mathematics?--Fan Mail, 1941-1959 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Whitman, G.B., 1961 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Whitney, Hassler (see "National Academy of Sciences"), 1961-1962 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Wiener, Norbert, 1941-1958 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Wienholz, Ernst, 1962-1967 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Wijngaarden, Andreas van, 1953-1958 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Willig, Paul, 1964-1966 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Wolkowisky, Jay, 1962-1963 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Woll, John, 1952-1953 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - "Work on Digital Computing Machines in Germany," N. Artin and Courant, 1947 (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - Wright Patterson Air Force Base, 1955 (Box 94, Folder 11)
    - WW-AMP Ex. Co., 1944 (Box 94, Folder 12)
    - "XYZ" Misc., 1942-1968 (Box 94, Folder 13)
    - Yang, C.N. (see "SUNY Stony Brook"), 1961-1969 (Box 94, Folder 14)
    - Yerevan Conference, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 15)
    - Yourgrau, Wolfgang--"The Nature of Mathematical Constants", 1957-1958 (Box 94, Folder 16)
    - Zagustin, A.--"Numerical Integration of Poisson's Equation", 1957 (Box 94, Folder 17)
    - Zagustin, Elena, 1957-1967 (Box 94, Folder 18)
    - Zagustin, Elena--"Estudio Sobre Cohetes", 1957 (Box 94, Folder 19)
    - Zagustin, Elena--"Funciones de Variable Compleja", 1958 (Box 94, Folder 20)
    - Zwahlen, Robert, 1951-1953 (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - Subseries B: Grants
    - AF-AFOSR-815-65, 1965-1966 (Box 94, Folder 22)
    - Div. Drafts and Proposals, 1958-1960 (Box 94, Folder 23)
    - National Carbon Research, 1955-1959 (Box 94, Folder 24)
    - NSF--Temporary Membership Plan, 1958-1959 (Box 94, Folder 25)
    - NSF G-6331--Temporary Membership MBCS, 1958-1960 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - NsG-412--MBCS, 1963-1966 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - NSF-GP-3485--Administration--Magnus, 1964-1965 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - NSF-GP-3485--MBCS--Magnus, 1964-1966 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - NSF-GP-27-Kline-Gov't: OH-Admin, 1957-1965 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - NSF-GE-8497--In-Service Institute, 1965-1966 (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - NSF-GP-733--Courant, Meth. of Math. Physics, 1962-1965 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - NSF-SP-733--Courant, Travel, 1963-1965 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - NSF-GU-35--J.J. Stoker Construction Funds, 1961-1966 (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - NsG-412--Administration, 1963-1964 (Box 95, Folder 10)
    - Research Corporation (1 of 2), 1945-1953 (Box 95, Folder 11)
    - Research Corporation (2 of 2), 1945-1953 (Box 95, Folder 12)
    - Rockefeller Fund Renewal, 1950-1953 (Box 95, Folder 13)
    - Shimmel Report--Impending Science Legislation, 1945 (Box 95, Folder 14)
    - Sloan Foundation, 1955-1956 (Box 95, Folder 15)
    - Smith, Rufus D. (NYU Provost), 1949-1951 (Box 95, Folder 16)
- Series III: Oversized Material
  - University of Breslau diploma, 1905 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - University of Zürich proof of attendance document, 1907 (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Certificate for Courant's Military Merit Cross, 1916 (Box 96, Folder 3)